ABOUT ME

Creative IT technician with 4 years of experience managing IT systems and one year crafting ITSM software at a small consultancy. Desire to use proven technical and communication skills to develop high quality business systems. Enthusiastic to learn new software, surmount engineering hurdles, and hunt down pesky bugs.

AWARDS & PUBS.

Airman of the Year - 961st AACS, Kadena AB, 2010

Jackson, E. D.; Green, S. C.; Prieto, A. L. Electrochemical Performance of Electrodeposited Zn4Sb3Films for Sodium-Ion Secondary Battery Anodes. ACS Applied Materials & Interfaces 2015, 7 (14), 7447–7450.

SKILLS

Languages:

React, Node.js HTML, CSS, Javascript, PostgreSQL, Python

Operating Systems:

Linux (Arch/Antergos), MS Windows

DevOps:

Git

IDEs/Text Editors:

VSCode, nVim

Misc:

Agile methodology

ScottGreen

IT Technician | Denver, CO

Projects

Star Wars App

Front-end displaying selectable cards which show more information when clicked.

Uses React

Face Recognition App

Register and login users, input photograph from with a URL and use the Clarifai API to identify faces in the photograph.

Uses React, Node.js, Express and PostgreSQL, hosted on Heroku: https://facerecognitionfrontend.herokuapp.com/

WORK HISTORY

(Sep. 2017 - Sep. 2018)

ASSOCIATE CONSULTANT - T4S Partners

- Used a declarative scripting language to design multiple back-end systems, including an auto-assignment ticketing system, REST API integration, and email parsing.
- Pair programmed in an end-to-end development pipeline, with Dev., Test and Prod. servers. Coordinated testing, deployment of features, and bug fixes for a SaaS business product.
- Troubleshot production-affecting service outages. Determined causes and implemented solutions, minimizing downtime and improving client relations.

(June 2008 - June 2012)

COMPUTER TECHNICIAN - USAF | Kadena, Japan and Beale, CA

 Operated in teams composed of varied specialties to maintain two AWACS aircraft and a DCGS system.

EDUCATION

(May, 2016)

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, CHEMISTRY - Colorado State University

- Organized study groups for advanced chemistry courses. Helped improve classmate's grades from C's to A's.
- ACS certified degree with courses in organic, inorganic and physical chemistry, biochemistry, calculus-based statistics and physics.

(Sep. 2016 – August 2017)

MATERIALS SCIENCE ENGINEERING - University of Washington

Advanced coursework in semiconductor theory and design.



